All right! You guys, it's starting to snow.
各位,外面开始下雪了
And look,Ugly Naked Guy is hanging candy canes.
快看啊,丑陋裸男在挂糖果藤
Where?
哪里?
Oh. Well.
哇. 不错
That's festive.
真有节日气氛
Guys,there's somebody I'd like you to meet.
各位我想介绍一个人给大家认识
Wait,wait. What is that?
等等…这是怎么回事?
-That's Marcel. Wanna say hi? -No,I don't.
-他叫马修,想和他打声招呼? -不,我不要
-He's cute! Where'd you get him? -My friend Bethel saved him from a lab.
-他好可爱,哪里得到他的? -我朋友贝瑟把它从实验室救出来的
That is so cruel.
真残忍
Why would a parent name their child Bethel?
为何有父母会将孩子取名为圣地(贝瑟)?
That monkey's got a Ross on his ass.
那猴子的屁股上长了个罗斯
Is he gonna live with you in your apartment?
罗斯,它要和你同住吗?
Yeah. It's been kind of quiet since Carol left.
对,卡萝离开後家里冷清清的
Why not get a roommate?
为何不找个室友?
You reach a certain age,having a roommate is just kind of pathet
人到一定的年纪后与室友同住是有点可悲(pathet)…
That's " pathet. " Sanskrit for " really cool way to live. "
抱歉,是pathet 在梵语中代表很酷的生活方式
The One With the Monkey
六人行 第1季 第10集 猴子
-=BT之家DRM小组 http://bbs.btbbt.com=- 荣誉出品 河马根据网络字幕微调制作
I' m doing new material tonight.
各位,我今天将唱全新的曲目
I have 1 2 songs about my mother's suicide and one about a snowman.
我写了12首关于我妈自杀的歌 及一首有关雪人的歌
You might wanna open with the snowman.
你最好先唱雪人
-Hi,Joey. -Hey,buddy.
-乔伊 -老兄
-So how'd it go? -I didn't get the job.
-如何? -我没得到那份工作
How could you not? You were Santa last year.
你怎可能会没得到?你是去年的圣诞老人
Some fat guy's sleeping with the store manager.
不知道哪个胖子和店经理有一腿
He's not even jolly. It's all political.
他根本无法逗人开心,这就是政治
-What are you gonna be? -One of his helpers.
-那么你扮演什么? -当他的助手
It's just such a slap in the face, you know?
就像是脸上的一个巴掌,你明白的?(真是耻辱)
Do you know what you' re doing for New Year's?
你们打算如何过新年?
Hey,what? What is wrong with New Year's?
什么?新年有什么不对劲吗?
You have Paolo. You don't have to face the pressure...
你有保罗.无须面对新年带来的压力
...of finding lips to kiss when the ball drops!
无须急着寻找有嘴唇的生物 便于在球落下那一刻有个亲嘴的对象
Man,I'm talking loud!
哦,我说得太大声了!
Paolo's gonna be in Rome this New Year's.
保罗新年时会在罗马
-I'll be just as pathetic as you. -Yeah,you wish.
-所以我将和各位一样可悲 -想得美
I've got an idea. Dinner.
我有个主意,聚餐
It's perfect. We'll put it between lunch and breakfast.
不错,我们可以把它放在午饭和早饭之间
I'm sick of being a victim of this Dick Clark holiday.
我不想再听到迪克拉克的疲劳轰炸
I say this year,we make a pact. Just the six of us. Dinner.
我说今年,我们约定.只有我们6个共进晚餐
-Sure. -Fine.
-当然 -好得
I was hoping for more enthusiasm.
我希望大家能更开心点
-Phoebe,you' re on. -Oh,good.
-菲比,该上台了 -哦,好的
Hi. Ladies and gentlemen, back by popular demand...
各位,回应大家要求
... Miss Phoebe Buffay.
菲比布费小姐
Hi. Thanks. Hi.
hi.谢谢.hi
I wanna start with a song that means a lot to me.
首先的这首歌在这种时节令我感慨万分
I made a man with eyes of coal
我做了一个人,眼睛是煤炭做的
And a smile so bewitching
他有谜样的微笑
How was I supposed to know
我如何能承受
That my mom was dead in the kitchen?
母亲死在厨房的事实
My mother's ashes
母亲的骨灰
Even her eyelashes
甚至是她的睫毛
Are resting in a little yellow jar
都安放在一个黄色的小骨灰坛
And sometimes when it's freezing
当有时天寒地冻
I feel a little sneezy
我感觉有点想打啧涕
And now I Excuse me? Excuse me? Yeah,noisy boys.
如今我…抱歉,吵闹的男人
Is it something you'd like to share with the group?
有什么想和大家分享的吗?
No. No,that's okay.
没.没,没事
If it's important enough while I'm playing...
如果有事如此重要 你们非在我唱歌时谈论
...it's important enough for everyone else.
那就重要的足以与我们分享
That guy's going home with a note.
那家伙铁定会带着一本注意事项回家去
-I was just saying -Speak up.
-我是告诉我朋友… -大声点行吗?
Sorry,l
抱歉,我
I was saying you were the most beautiful woman I'd ever seen.
我告诉我朋友：你是我见过最漂亮的女孩
And he said that Daryl Hannah...
他说黛瑞汉娜…黛瑞汉娜
...was the most beautiful woman he'd ever seen.
是他见过最美的女人
I said I liked her in Splash, but not Wall Street.
我说我喜欢“美人鱼”中的她 但“华尔街”就没那么喜欢了
I thought she had a hard quality.
她没那种硬派气质
While Daryl is beautiful in a conventional way...
黛瑞汉娜是传统的美
...you are luminous with a kind of delicate grace.
而你散发出高雅的气质
Then that's when you started yelling.
然后你就叫我们了
We're gonna take a short break.
休息片刻
That guy's going home with more than a note.
那小伙得到得远不止注意事项了啊(抱得美人归)
Come here,Marcel. Sit here.
过来,马修,坐这儿
I can't believe he hasn't kissed you yet.
拜托,没想到他还没亲你
By my sixth date with Paolo, he'd already named both my breasts.
我第6次和保罗约会时 他就为我的双峰取了名字
Did I just share too much?
我分享太多了吗?
Just a smidge.
一点点
David's,like,a scientist guy. He's very methodical.
大卫是个科学家,做事一丝不苟
-I think it's romantic. -Me too!
-我认为这很浪漫 -我也这么想!
Did you ever see An Officer and a Gentleman?
你们看过军官与绅士吗?
He's kind of like the guy I went to see that with.
他就是我心目中的白马王子
Except he's smarter and gentler and sweeter.
除了他更聪明,温柔体贴
I just wanna be with him all the time.
我只想整天和他厮守在一起
You know,day and night. And night and day.
不管是白天或夜晚,还是夜晚或白天
And special occasions.
还有特别的日子
I see. You're gonna ask him to New Year's.
等等,我知道了 你邀他共渡新年,对不?
-She's gonna break the pact. -No! No,no.
-她想抛弃我们 -不!不,不
No. Yeah,could I just?
不…对,我可以…
-Yeah. I already asked Janice. -What?
-好吧,因为我已约了珍妮丝 -什么?
This was a pact! This was your pact!
这是一个约定!这是你们的约定!
I couldn't handle the pressure. I snapped!
我耐不住寂寞,我毁约了
But that was the worst breakup in history!
可是珍妮丝…你们的分手不是糟透了?
I'm not saying it was a good idea. I snapped!
我没说这是个好主意,我毁约了
Hi,sorry I'm late.
抱歉,我迟到了
Too many jokes.
太滑稽了
Must mock Joey.
快取笑乔伊
Nice shoes,huh?
鞋子正点吧
God,you're killing me!
我快笑死了
Ross,he's playing with my spatulas again!
罗斯,它又玩我的铲子
-He's not gonna hurt them,right? -Do you always have to bring him?
-它又不会玩坏的 -你非得每次都带它来不可吗?
I didn't wanna leave him alone. We had our first fight this morning.
我不想留下他一个人? 我们早上才吵了一架
It has to do with my working late. I said some things that I didn't mean.
一定是我加班惹的祸 我说了不该说的话
He threw some feces.
它就朝我扔一坨屎
If you're working late, I can look in on him.
如果你必须加班,我可以替你照顾它
That would be great!
这太好了
But make sure it seems like you're there to see him.
如果你去照顾它, 要装成一付去找它的样子
You're not doing it for me.
不能让它知道你是在帮我忙
Okay. But if he asks, I'm not going to lie.
好,但它如果问起 我可就要直话直说了
But you can't actually test this theory.
但我们仍无法测试这个理论
T oday's particle accelerators aren't powerful enough...
因为今日粒子加速的速度
-...to simulate these conditions. -I have a question then.
-仍无法模拟出这样的情况 -好,我有个问题
-Yeah? -Do you plan on kissing me ever?
你打算亲我吗?
That's definitely a valid question, and the answer...
这是个正当而合理的问题 答案是…
...would be yes. Yes,I was.
答案是…是的.对,我曾想过
But I wanted it to be this phenomenal kiss...
但我要让这非凡的吻…
...at a phenomenal moment because it's you.
发生在非凡的时刻,因为是你
Sure.
当然
The longer I waited,the more phenomenal the kiss had to be.
但等得越久亲吻就越非凡
Now,it's just gotta be one of those things where l...
而在此时此地,我想…
...sweep everything off the table.
…扫去桌上的一切,将你丢在上面
And I'm not really a sweeping sort of fella.
但我不是会扫去一切,那种猴急的男人
David,I think you are a sweeping sort of fella.
大卫,我想你是
I mean,you're a sweeper trapped inside a physicist's body.
你是被困在物理学家体内的猛男
-Really? -I'm sure.
-真的? -没错,我确定
You should just do it. Just throw me.
你应该解放出来,把我丢上去吧
-Now? -Yeah,right now. Just....
-现在? -对,现在
Okay. Okay. Okay.
好.好.好
You know what? This is really expensive.
这东西很贵的
And this was a gift.
这个是人家送的
-Now you' re just tidying up. -Okay.
-你在清理场地? -好吧,管他的
-You want me to throw you? -I can hop.
-你想让我丢上去还是自己跳上去? -我自己跳好了
T ell me something,what does " no-date pact" mean to you?
告诉我,“没有约会的约定”对你们有何意义?
It's just that Chandler and Phoebe have somebody.
钱德有对象,菲比也有对象
I thought I'd ask Fun Bobby.
所以我约了搞笑巴比
-Your ex-boyfriend? -Yeah.
-搞笑巴比?你的前任男友搞笑巴比? -对
-You know more than one Fun Bobby? -I happen to know a Fun Bob.
-你还认识其他的搞笑巴比? -我认识搞笑巴伯
-Okay. Here we go. -There's no room for milk.
-来了 -太满了,我没法加牛奶了
There. Now there is.
好了,这下可以了
So on our no-date evening, three of you now have dates.
所以在这个没有约会的晚上,三人另有节目
-Four. -Five.
-四人 -五人
Sorry. Paolo's catching an earlier flight.
抱歉,保罗提早搭飞机回来
And I met this really hot single mom at the store.
而我在商场遇上―个火辣辣的单亲妈妈
What's an elf to do?
我这个小精灵怎能抗拒?
So I'll be the only one alone when the ball drops?
这么说球落下那一刻 我是唯一一个孤零零的家伙?
We'll have a big party, and no one will know who's with who.
我们将举行盛大的派对 而且没人知道到底知道谁和谁
I'll know. This is so not what I needed right now.
我知道,而且这不是我现在需要知道的
-What's the matter? -Oh,it's Marcel.
-你怎么了? -都是马修
He's angry with me. I have no idea why. He keeps shutting me out.
它生我的气了 我不知道为什么 它一直不让我进门
He's walking around all the time, dragging his hands.
它拖着双手不断绕圈子
That's weird. I had a blast with him.
真是诡异 我前几天晚上还跟它相处愉快
-Really? -We played,watched TV.
-真的? -我们一起玩,看电视
That juggling thing is amazing.
杂耍那一部份真是太精彩了
What juggling thing?
什么杂耍?
With the socks? I figured you taught him that.
拿袜子当球耍,我以为是你教它的
No.
我没有
It wasn't that big a deal. Just socks. And a melon.
这也不算什么,只是拿袜子罢了 还有一颗香瓜
-Phoebe! -Max. Do you know everybody?
-菲比 -马克斯,认识大家吗?
No. Have you seen David?
不认识,你看见大卫吗?
He hasn't been around.
没有,他没在这儿
If you see him,tell him to pack. We are going to Minsk.
看见他时告诉他快打包,我们要去明斯克
-Minsk? -Minsk. It's in Russia.
-明斯克? -在苏联
I know where Minsk is.
我知道明斯克在哪儿
We got the grant. Three years,all expenses paid.
我们已申请到奖助金 全额赞助我们三年
And if you're gonna do Minsk, that's the way to go.
如果你们去明斯克就是这样去的
-So when do you leave? -January 1 st.
-你们何时去明斯克 -元旦(新年第一天)
-Hello? -What? Hey. Hi.
-有人吗?
-What are you doing here? -Max told me about Minsk.
-你来这儿干什么? -马克斯告诉我明克斯的事了
Congratulations! This is so exciting!
恭喜了,真叫人兴奋
It'd be even more exciting if we were going.
能去的话会更叫人兴奋
Oh,you're not going? Oh,why?
你不去了?为什么?
T ell her. " I don't wanna go...
告诉她,“我不打算去…”
...to work with Lipson, Yamaguchi and Flank.
…去和李本斯亚马古基与法朗克共事
I wanna stay and make out with my girlfriend! "
我要留下来和我的女友培养感情
Okay,thank you,Max. Thank you.
够了,马克斯,谢谢
So you're really not going?
你真的不去?
I don't know what I'm gonna do. I just....
我也不知道,我只是…
How can I leave you? I just found you.
我怎么能离开你?我才刚刚遇到你
Oh,David. But what are you gonna do?
大卫.你决定怎么办?
I don't know. You decide.
我不知道.你决定
-Don't do that. -But l' m asking you.
-别这样 -我是在求你
-I can't make a decision. Just -Okay. Stay.
-我不能那么做 -好吧,留下来
-Stay. -Stay.
-留下来 -留下来
Getting so good at that!
你进步神速啊!
It was Max's stuff.
这是麦克斯的东西
I love this artichoke thing.
我喜欢菊芋
Don't tell me what's in it. The diet starts tomorrow.
别告诉我里面是什么 我明天才开始节食
You remember Janice.
记得珍妮丝?
Vividly.
历历在目
-How are you? -I am fantastic.
-感觉怎么样? -我现在感觉…
Now.
…太奇妙了！
It's amazing. We've been back together for what...
真的很奇妙.我们又一起回到了…
-...Iike 1 0 minutes,and -ls that all?
-…就像还有十分钟 -就这些?
It's like we were never apart.
就好像我俩从来没有分开过一样
Of course,we were,but Forgive and forget.
当然,我们会,原谅并且忘记
Well,forget.
好的,忘记
-Hi. -Hi,l' m Sandy.
-Hi -Hi,我是珊蒂
Sandy,hi. Come on in.
珊蒂,请进
-You brought your kids. -Yeah. That's okay,right?
-你把孩子都带来了 -对,可以吗?
-Party! -That thing is not coming in here!
-我来了! -这东西不可以进来
This is how you greet guests?
东西?你都这样招呼客人吗?
If I showed up with my new girlfriend, she wouldn't be welcome?
我问你,如果我带着新女友来 你也不欢迎她进来?
Your new girlfriend wouldn't urinate on my coffee table.
你的新女友不会尿在我的咖啡桌上
He was more embarrassed about that than anyone.
它已经够难为情了,行吗?
And for him to have the courage to walk back in here...
它已鼓足勇气回到这里
...Iike nothing happened
就当一切都没发生过一样
All right. All right. Just keep him away from me.
好,叫它离我远点就是了
Thank you. Come on,Marcel.
谢谢.来,马修
What do you say you and I mingle?
咱们去交际一下吧
All right,I'll catch up with you later.
好吧,待会儿见
Oh,my gosh! Rachel,honey,are you okay?
天啊,瑞秋,你没事吧?
-Where's Paolo? -Rome. Jerk missed his flight.
-保罗在哪儿? -罗马.那混蛋没赶上飞机
And then your face exploded?
然后你的脸就爆炸了?
No.
不是
Okay. I was at the airport getting into a cab...
我在机场要进入计程车时
...when this woman,this blond planet with a pocketbook...
一个带着一本书的金发女人
...starts yelling. Something about how it was her cab first.
开始对我大叫,说是她先拦到的
The next thing,she just starts pulling me out by my hair!
然后她就开始扯我的头发
And I was blowing my attack whistle thingy...
我拿出口哨猛吹
...and three more cabs show up.
结果又来了三辆计程车
So as I'm going to get into a cab, she tackles me!
我要进入车时,她又展开攻击
And I hit my head on the curb and cut my lip on my whistle.
结果我撞上了马路牙子 嘴唇被口中的哨子弄伤
Everybody having fun at the party?
大家玩得还愉快吧?
-Are people eating my dip? -Yes.
-有人吃我的泡菜吗 -有的
There.
那里
-That looks okay,right? -You went a bit wide on the lipstick.
-这看起来还行,对不? -你唇膏涂的有点厚了
-Oh,I did? -Yeah.
-是吗? -有点
It's hard for me to tell. My eye's closing up.
我很难看清楚,我眼睛肿起来了
Let me get it for you.
我来给你画吧
-Ow! -Okay.
-喔! -好了
You know what? It looks fine.
你们觉得怎么样?看起来不错
Okay,here we go.
好吧,我们出去吧
Screw Paolo, screw the psycho cab lady.
去他的保罗,去他的心理变态计程车女人
It's New Year's Eve. Let's have a good time.
这是新年前夜,我们过得开心点
-Okay,here we go. -Okay.
-ok,我们走吧 -ok
All right,there you go. This way.
好吧,来,这边走
Here you go.
这边走
When I saw you at the store last week...
我上周在商场看见你时
...it was the first time I ever mentally undressed an elf.
那或许是我第一次想像裸体的小精灵
-Wow,that's dirty. -Yeah.
-真淫荡 -是的
孩子
Hey,kids.
He doesn't have to spend the whole evening with me...
我没说他得整晚和我待在一起
... but at least check in.
但至少也得来问候一声
There you are!
原来你在这儿
You got away from me.
你从我身边逃跑了
-But you found me. -Here,Ross,take our picture.
-但又被你逮到了 -罗斯,帮我们照一张
Smile. You' re on Janice Camera.
笑一个,你在珍妮丝的相机中了
Kill me. Kill me now.
杀了我吧,现在就杀了我
Hi,l' m Rachel.
hi,我叫瑞秋
So whose friend are you?
你是谁的朋友啊?
Look at me,spilling everywhere.
看看我,洒的到处都是
Everybody,it's Fun Bobby!
各位,搞笑巴比来了
Hey,sorry I'm late. But my grandfather...
抱歉,我迟到了.我祖父他
...died about two hours ago.
他在两小时前过世了
But I couldn't get a flight out till tomorrow,so here I am.
明天才有飞机,所以我来了
Hey,Fun Bobby! How's it going,man? Whoa! Who died?
搞笑巴比,近来可好?谁死了?
It's gonna be an open casket, you know?
他棺材将暂时不盖上
So at least I'll get to see him again.
所以我至少可以再见他最后一面
Bobby? Fun Bobby?
巴比?搞笑巴比?
Let me talk to you for just a sec.
我们简单聊聊
I recently lost a grandparent myself...
我最近奶奶也刚刚去世了…
...so I really know exactly how you feel.
所以我很能体会你现在的感受
But you' re really bringing the party down.
但是你确实把聚会的气氛弄得很糟
-l' m sorry. -Yeah,yeah,okay.
-对不起 -好吧
There you go. There you go.
这就行了.这就行了
I' m gonna blow this one up and write " Reunited " in glitter.
我要在上面哈口气,然后写上“破镜重圆”
All right,Janice,that's it!
珍妮丝,够了
Janice. Janice.
珍妮丝…珍妮丝…
Hey,Janice,when I invited you, I didn't think it meant
珍妮丝,我邀你来并不代表我们…
Oh,no!
哦，不…
I' m sorry you misunderstood.
抱歉,让你误会了
You listen to me! You listen to me!
你听我说…你听我说…
One of these times,it's just gonna be your last chance with me!
这可能是你我最后一次共处了
Will you give me the thing?
那东西可以给我吗?
-Hi,Max. -Yoko.
-马克斯 -小野洋子
I've decided to go to Minsk without you.
我决定自己去明斯克了
-Wow. -lt won't be the same...
-喔 -少了你将不太一样…
... but it will still be Minsk. Happy New Year.
…但明斯克还是明斯克 新年快乐
-Are you all right? -Yeah,l' m fine. I' m fine.
-你还好吧? -没事,我没事,我没事
Come on.
来
-You' re going to Minsk. -No,l' m not going to Minsk.
-你去明克斯吧 -不,我不去了
You are so going to Minsk.
你一定要去明斯克
You belong in Minsk. You can't stay here just for me.
你属于明斯克 你不能因为我而留下来
If I go,I have to break up with you.
如果我走,就代表我必须与你分手
-And I can't break up with you. -Yes,you can.
-但我不能和你分手. -是的,你可以的
Just say," Phoebe,I love you, but my work is my life.
只用说,“菲比,我爱你, 但是工作是我的生命”
That's what I have to do. "
“这是我必须做的.”
And I say,"Your work? How can you say that? "
然后我说,“你的工作?你竟说出这种话?”
Then you say," I have no choice. Can't you understand that? "
接着你说,“我没有选择. 难道你不了解吗?”
And I say," No! No! I can't understand that! "
我说,“不!不!我不了解!”
-Ow. -Sorry.
-喔 -对不起
And then you put your arms around me.
然后你抱住我…
-Then you put your arms around me. -Oh,sorry.
-然后你抱住我… -哦,对不起
And then you tell me you love me and you'll never forget me.
然后你对我说你爱我 你永远不会忘记我
I'll never forget you.
我永远不会忘记你
Then you say that you have to go...
你又说现在已接近午夜,你必须走了
... because you don't wanna start the year with me if you can't finish it.
你不想与我共渡新 因为你实在狠不下心离开
I' m gonna miss you, you scientist guy.
我会想你的,科学家
Hi,Dick Clark in Times Square.
我是迪克拉克 在时代广场为你做实况报导
We're in a virtual snowstorm of confetti here in Times Square.
时代广场这儿的五彩纸片纷纷落下
It gets better every....
一年比一年进步
Here you go,kids.
好好睡吧，孩子
And then the peacock bit me.
然后孔雀就咬了我
Please kiss me at midnight!
请在午夜吻我
-You seen Sandy? -I don't know how to tell you this...
-看见珊蒂没? -我不知该如何告诉你
... but she's in the bedroom getting it on with Max.
她和马克斯在摩妮卡的房里
Oh,I did know how to tell you.
酷,你看我还是告诉你了
-Hey,everybody,the ball is dropping. -What?
-各位,大球要掉了 -什么?
The ball is dropping!
大球要掉了
In 20 seconds,it'll be midnight.
再过20秒钟就是午夜
And the moment of joy is upon us.
兴奋的时刻即将到来
Looks like that no-date pact worked out.
看起来没有约会的约定奏效了啊
Everybody looks so happy. I hate that!
大家好像都很开心,我不喜欢
Not everybody is happy. Hey,Bobby!
不是大家都开心,嘿,巴比
four,three,two...
4…3…2…
...one! Happy New Year!
…1!新年快乐
I thought I'd throw this out. I' m no math whiz...
我这么说好了,我不是数学大师
... but I do believe there are three girls and three guys right here.
但我相信这儿有3对男女
I don't feel like kissing anyone tonight.
今晚我不想亲任何人
-I can't kiss anyone. -So,I'm kissing everyone?
-我无法亲任何人 -我就该亲大家?
No,you can't kiss Ross. That's your brother.
不,你不能亲罗斯,他是你哥
So now everybody's getting kissed but me.
太好了,大家都亲,除我之外
Somebody kiss me.
谁来亲我…
Somebody kiss me! It's midnight! Somebody kiss me!
谁来亲我…现在是午夜… 谁来亲我…
All right! All right!
好吧,来吧
There!
这里!
I wanted this to work so much.
我真的希望这样能够奏效
I'm still in there.
我还在那里
Changing his diapers. Picking his fleas.
替它换尿布,替它抓跳蚤
But he's just phoning it in.
但它却视为理所当然
It's hard that something you love so much doesn't love you back.
深爱某人却得不到回报 真是令人难过
I think that bitch cracked my tooth.
我想那个贱人打断了我的牙齿